Cheers and Sighs
決行！破滅か？勝利か？
Which will it be?!
Abject failure, or victory!?
今 始まる
坂崎の人食い沼との死闘！
Sakazaki's duel with the Man-eating Bog begins!
始まる
It begins!
フン 坂崎のオヤジらしい
Looks like it's old man Sakazaki.
陽気な博奕だ
He seems like he's having the time of his life.
でも あの台は…
シッ
But that machine...
いいか カイジくん
Got it, Kaiji?
Don't just rush in!
すぐ横に かぶりつくようなマネは
やめてくれよ
カイジくんは
そろりそろり来てくれればいい
Just kind of gradually drift toward me!
急いではダメだ
Don't rush it!
怪しまれさえしなければ
うまくいく
As long as you don't attract their attention, we're fine!
渡しも最後の仕上げの開始も
うまくやり果たせるはず
You can pull off the handover and the cleanup!
また来たぜ クルーンに
He's in the trays again!
始めてから大して経ってないのに
もう３回 いや４回か？
It never lets anyone through easy, but he's already landed three down there!
No, four!
ああ いつもの沼じゃねえ
大甘だぜ 今日の釘
The Bog isn't usually like this! The pins today must be set for a winner!
こりゃあ ひょっとすると
ひょっとするぜ！
Maybe! Just maybe!
いけ いけ いけ いけ！
Go for it!
Here we go!
きとる きとる きとる！
今日は100に１つの特異日
設定Ａの日
Today's one in a hundred!
Setting A... I've never seen this many balls make it in!
わしも見たことがない
この入り 確率
I'll win it! I'll win that 550—no, that 600 million!
勝てる！５億5000　いや ６億だ
よし クリアだ
最初のハードルはクリア
All right, we're over the first hurdle.
The Bog has three hurdles!
沼には３つのハードルがある
Its first defense:
その第１関門は
釘の森
the Forest of Pins!
He's through the Forest of Pins!
釘の森を突破してる
通常は60から100に１玉しか
通過できない
Normally, only one of every 60 or 100 balls makes it through!
急所は一番上のぶっこみの釘と
The key is the top pin, the one it hits first, and the six or seven guarding the path,
役モノへの入り口周辺の６～７本
and then the two by the gate.
そして入り口の２本
But today, they're more forgiving than usual.
しかし 今日はそれがぬるい
寄りがいい　吸い寄せられていく
The balls are falling right where we want them! Almost like they're being sucked in!
30に１つは行っている
One in thirty is making it through!
これが２番目のハードル
This is the second hurdle!
クルーンの入り口に座り込み
玉をはじく気まぐれな番人
Two blocking flippers, guarding the entrance to the trays!
厄介な あまのじゃく
ランダムに道を閉ざす面倒な関所
Two troublesome demons!
An annoying barrier, closing at random!
しかし 長年見てきた
おっちゃんの話では
But pops has been watching for years, and he says they let about one in three through.
おおよそ３つに１つ
クルーンに通す確率らしい
So one-third of 1/30th of balls make it through the Forest of Pins to the trays.
とすれば 釘の森を抜けて
クルーンにたどり着くのは
30分の１かける３分の１
That's one in ninety!
90分の１
He got another one in!
また入った
All that's left is the big baddie...
残るは あの大仰な役モノ
The real core of the Bog, its toughest part...
この沼の目玉　最大の難関
難攻不落 最後の砦
The impregnable fortress, the triple trays!
３段クルーン
１段目が３分の１の確率
The first lets one of three balls through.
２段目が４分の１
The second, one of four.
And the third... The last tray, and the key to the 600 million... One in five.
３段目 入れば６億という
最終クルーンは５分の１
Three by four by five... One in sixty odds.
３かける４かける５　60分の１
こいつを落とさなければ
勝ちはない
But we can't win without beating it.
Factor in the odds of even hitting the trays, and the whole machine is one in 5,400.
クルーンに届く確率をかけると
5400分の１
5400玉に１玉 大当たりというのが
今の沼の計算上の確率
How the Bog's set up now, one ball in 5,400 hits the jackpot.
お客さま 台を叩くのは…
Sir, no striking the machine!
Oh, sorry, I got carried away.
すまんすまん　つい
どうぞ
Here.
ついでにビールくれんか？
は？
Hey, would ya go get me a beer?
ネジの巻き直しだ　ビール！
あっ はい
Something to cool me back down! A beer!
Of course!
This irritation, this impatience... He's mostly faking it.
このイラ立ち 焦燥は
なかば おっちゃんの演技
予定どおりの行動
He's doing exactly what we planned.
All right, let's get this started!
さあて やるか
もう一度
Here we go again!
よーし いいぞオヤジ
めげんな！
Go for it, old man!
You can do it!
頼むで　井草八幡 力を！
Please! Give me power, Igusa Hachiman!
さあ 出すぞ６億
後押し 頼むで　みんな！
I'm getting that 600 million!
Cheer me on, everyone!
The Bog! The Bog!
入った　１段目だ！
He made it to the first tray!
No, the second!
２段目も行った！
今日 初の３段目！
おおっ
The first one to the third today!
持っとれ
Hey, get me another!
頼む　頼む　頼む
Come on! Come on!
Please! Come on!
頼む 来い！
クソッ
まだまだ これからだ
I've got more where that came from!
いけ いけ いけ いけ！
Go for it!
It never goes in?
入らない？
ああ 入らない
Never.
It never, ever goes in the hole on the bottom tray.
あの３段目のクルーンの最後
１番下のクルーンの辺りは
絶対に入らない
I've proven that on my mockup.
それは俺の仮想沼で証明済み
俺の偽物は作りが雑で
ごくたまに入ったりしたが
It isn't quite a perfect copy, so once in a while it makes it in, but...
本物の沼はその辺りが
きっちり仕上げられていて
On the real Bog, they've been very careful
玉のコントロール
つまりクルーンへの落下速度
to control the angle and speed the ball enters the bottom tray at.
導入角度が寸分違わず 毎回一緒
その結果 その玉は必ず外れる
Because of this, the ball always misses.
まあ大体 ５周と５分の１の所で
玉は推進力を失い 穴に落ちる
The ball just doesn't have the energy left to make it out of that final 1-in-5 chance.
ごくたまに
その手前か 玉足が伸びて
Once in a while, it makes it to the hole before the winner,
当たり穴の手前の穴まで
行くことがあるが
ブレはその範囲
決して当たりには届かない
but bends in the tray there make sure it doesn't go any further.
But on the other hand, if we play with that centrifugal force a little bit...
逆に言うなら
その遠心力の玉の回る力を
歪ませることができれば入り得る
It'll make it in.
それには台を開けて
何か細工するのが一番いいが
Opening it up and tweaking things would work best,
あの台はカメラと店員によって
24時間 厳重に監視されている
but that machine has workers and cameras watching it 24/7.
打つ時以外は
誰も近づくこともできん
No one's even allowed close unless they're playing it.
となれば 古典的だが
これしかあるまい
So this may be the oldest trick in the book, but it's the only one we've got.
磁石？
そう こいつが有効
Magnets?
Yeah. These'll do the trick.
If I hold a strong magnet up to the glass, it'll bend the path of the ball.
強力な磁石を
ガラス越しにかざせば
玉の軌道 遠心力は必ず歪む
Then the Bog will pay out like it should.
そうなれば あの沼も
本来の確率で出る台になる
敵はそれが怖いから 打つ者に
They're afraid of this happening, so they check players for magnets.
磁気チェックを
義務づけているんだ
だが 打つ者には厳しくとも
やじ馬はノーマーク
But they're so focused on the gambler that they ignore the crowd.
ノーチェックなんだな これが
They don't check 'em at all.
だったら渡してもらえばいい
ノーマークのやじ馬から磁石を
So I get a magnet from the crowd.
打ち手の横には
いつも店員が張り付いている
There's always an employee standing there watching the player.
Se it can't be out in plain sight.
だから 抜き身の磁石じゃダメだ
ちょっとした工夫が必要
We need a trick.
And this is it.
それが これだ
This is a fake beer with a magnet in it that we can sneak by them.
底をくり抜き
磁石を仕込んだゴトビール
We swap it while I'm playing.
こいつを勝負の最中に
交換するのさ
うまい手だろ？
Great idea, huh?
あのすり替え 気づかれなかった
The handoff...
They didn't notice.
Not the house, not anyone.
敵にも誰にも
最初の渡しは成功
The first part worked.
カイジは さりげなく坂崎から離れ
Kaiji nonchalantly walks away from Sakazaki.
店側の人間の動き 挙動に
怪しいことがないかをチェック
Moving with the crowd, he keeps a poker face.
遠巻きに坂崎を見守る
Then he watches Sakazaki from a distance.
It's here! My secret weapon is in my hand!
さあ 来た　わしの武器
秘密兵器がついに わしの手に
Here's where it really starts!
ここからが本当の勝負
いいか カイジくん
当たれば６億　大変な騒ぎになる
You ready, Kaiji? When I hit the 600 million, it'll be a real scene.
狂喜乱舞 大混乱 乱痴気騒ぎ
A flap! A kerfluffle! A pandemonium!
While everyone's still confused, you come back
その混乱に乗じて
カイジくんが戻ってきて
わしのカバンの上に置いた
磁石入りビールと
and swap the fake magnet beer on top of my bag for your own, again!
自分のビールを再度 すり替え
現場から離れる
Then get out of there, while the staff gets there and quiets things down.
店の連中が駆けつけて騒ぎを収め
その後 わしを身体検査しても
後の祭り　何も出やせん
Then when they go to check me, it's already too late.
They won't find a thing.
その頃 カイジくんは店の外
証拠は完全に消える
By that time, you're already outside.
The proof's already gone.
そう　わしは満座の前で
身の潔白を証明し 獲得するんだ
Yes! I'll come up clean in front of everyone, and then I'll cash in!
６億を！
All 600 million!
大当たりは5400玉に１玉
これが今日の沼の確率
One ball in 5,400... That's how many will hit the jackpot in the Bog today.
5,400 balls at 4,000 yen each is 21,600,000 yen.
１玉4000円が5400発で2160万
この確率どおりなら 2160万で
一度は大当たりが出現する
At today's odds, there's a jackpot for every 21,600,000 yen pumped in.
おっちゃんが最終的に
用意した金は5000万
And pops has 50,000,000 yen with him.
負けるわけがねえ これだけあれば
He can't lose.
Not as long as he has this!
来た 来た 来た！
３段目だ！
Here it comes!
The third tray!
いけ！
Go for it!
All right! Activate, magnet beer!
よし 発動！磁石入りビール
歪ませろ 玉の軌道 流れを！
Bend that ball's path! Its flow!
Bend it! Lead that ball straight up Victory Road!
曲げろ　曲げて導け
当たりへと続く
ビクトリーロードへ！
あー！
クッソー
Damn! Did it not change the spin enough!?
回転の歪みが足りなかったのか？
なら もう少し近づけて
今度は もう少し近づけて…
Then I've just gotta hold it a little bit closer! Just a little closer!
That's enough. Let's go.
もういい　行こう
はい
Yes.
ハァ… これで
よかったのかもしれない
This might be good. They were too close.
主任がいる所が近すぎた
It's better if he hits the jackpot when they're further away.
できるなら 大当たりは
連中が消えてからの方が望ましい
They're paying attention. And it's obvious why if you look at the rules.
敵は警戒している
それは あのプレーヤーへの
注意書きを見ても明らか
Rule #1! Cheats such as magnets or batteries are banned!
注意書き その１
セル 磁石などの
あらゆるゴト行為の禁止
その２　台を叩く 蹴るなど
Rule #2! Punching, kicking, or otherwise jolting the machine is banned!
あらゆる衝撃を与える行為の禁止
その３
故意 不可抗力にかかわらず
Rule #3! Whether intentional or not, modifying, damaging, or oiling balls is banned!
玉に何らかの細工 傷を付けたり
油を塗ったりすることは禁止
So they're afraid.
つまり 敵は恐れてるんだ
３段目 クルーンの回転が
歪むことを
Afraid someone will mess with the third tray...
And of course, there's this last part.
そして極めつけは この一文
For customers who obey these rules,
以上のことを
お守りいただけるお客様には
その方がプレーしている限り
no matter what the cost to this casino is,
どんなに当カジノにとって
不都合であろうと
ガラス戸を開けての釘調整等
as long as they play we will never perform acts such as
一切の操作 変更はいたしません
removing the glass and modifying the pin layout.
安心してお遊びください
Please play with full confidence.
This confidence, this conviction!
この自信 確信
言い換えるなら ３段目は
クルーンの絶対性さえ保てれば
It's because as long as the third tray keeps working, no one will ever win!
100％入らない
そういう敵の自信が透けて見える
I can see right through them!
なら 逆にありなんだ
That's how I know this magnet-beer plan to mess with the third tray has a chance!
３段目を無力化する
この磁石入りビール作戦が
Sakazaki's first ten million packy are spent!
坂崎が購入した しょっぱなの
1000万パッキーがついに尽きる
But with that ten million, he sent three balls to the third tray!
だが この1000万で坂崎は
三度 ３段目に運んだ！
お客様 どうなさいますか？
おやめになりますか？それとも…
Sir.
What will you do?
え… ええ？バカ　何 寝言 言う！
What, are you retarded?
今日は心中なんだ
誰がやめるかよ
This is my last hurrah! I'm not gonna quit!
Gimme another ten million packy!
持ってこい 1000万パッキー
し… しかし…
しかしもクソもあるか さっさと…
But...
But what? Hurry it up!
追加だ
え？
He wants more!
Bring another ten million packy!
お渡ししろ 1000万パッキーを
あ… はい
Okay...
2000万以上？
More than twenty million?
どういうことだ？
What's going on?
お前らの調べじゃ
あのオヤジのリミットは
Didn't you say you checked him out and he only had twenty million?
2000万だったんじゃないのか？
はい 確かにそうだったんですが
Yes, he did, but...
どこかで都合をつけたのか
もう2000か3000万は…
Somehow, he got his hands on another twenty or thirty...
そういうことなら
搾り取れるだけ搾り取れ
If he wants to burn it, we're glad to take it off his hands.
Hold off on the usual.
例の操作は延期だ
ブロックは しばらく待て
Don't activate the block yet.
なっ 何？
What?
Crap! They see straight through it!
マズい　筒抜けだ
知ってやがった 敵は
Our attempt, even our funds! We'll get killed!
俺たちの挑戦を 軍資金のことも
殺される
おっちゃん
Pops!
こっち見ろ おっちゃん
Look up here, pops!
This is an emergency! Call it off!
緊急事態だ　中止だ！
At least stop to use the bathroom! We need to plan!
立って トイレ行くんだ
作戦タイムだ
Shit!
クソッ ダメだ！全然 気づかない
He isn't noticing!
また３段目だ！
よーし いけ！
The third tray again!
All right!
Get up, pops!
おっちゃん 立ってくれ
Take a break! We need to take a break!
中止だ　ここはとりあえず中止だ
おっちゃん
Pops!
坂崎は立たない　カイジを無視！
Sakazaki does not stand! He ignores Kaiji!
続行　あくまで続行！
He holds steady! Steady until the end!
止まらない　もう止まらない！
He will not stop! He cannot be stopped!
火がついてしまった 博奕打ちの心
A fire has sparked is his gambler's heart!
熱 欲 直感に！
Passion! Greed!
Intuition!
Quit bugging me!
邪魔くさい！今 立てるかよ！
There's no way I can stand up now!
来とるんだ　わしは今
I've got it!
Look at how good I'm doing!
今 この好調　この流れ
Look at how it's going!
来とる　３段目にも続々と
It's gonna happen!
Look at how many balls I'm landing in the third tray!
I can't stand up now! No pachinko player would stand up!
今は立てない　ここで立っては
パチンカーではない！
ダメだ
It's no good...
加熱！加熱する勝負！
It overheats! The battle overheats!
博奕 野望 狂気
Gambling! Ambition! Madness!
回る銀玉！回る欲望！
Spiraling balls, spiraling lust!
そして 気がつけば…
Then, he snaps back to reality!
The extravagance, the waste!
散財！浪費！
ついえる
追加の1000万パッキーも！
Another 10,000,000 packy gone!
Will that be all for today, sir?
お客様 お引き揚げですか？
バカ　冗談はよせ
Quit pulling my leg.
小便タイム　小休止だ
I'm just taking a leak. I need a break.
何の用だ？
水を差すようなことしやがって
What's your problem!? You're messing with my flow!
I can't focus with you jumping around like that!
お前がチョロチョロするから
集中できんかったわ！
流れが変わったんだ あれで
That's what's messing things up!
あの茶々で
You and your distractions!
おっちゃん
やめた方がいいかもな もう
Pops...
We might be better off giving up.
あ？やめた方がいい？
Huh? Giving up?
何を言い出すんだ！
やめた方がいいだ？
What do you mean, giving up!?
知られていたんだ
They're on to us.
They know you're trying to take down the Bog.
おっちゃんが沼に挑戦することが
They even know how much money you've got.
軍資金の額までな　早い話
To cut a long story short, the guy you thought was on your side set you up.
おっちゃんが味方だと
思っていた従業員は向こうの手先
設定Ａの情報も
Even telling you about setting A was just to lure you in.
言うなら
おっちゃんを誘い出す まき餌
ワナだったってことだ
It's a trap!
おまけに敵は ブロックは待てとか
何とか言ってた
And they're talking about a block or something too.
ブロック？ブロックって何や？
Block? What the hell's a block?
Probably means they can shut off the "luck" you've been having with the flip of a switch.
俺も何のことか分からないが
敵はその気になれば
今の好調を止め得るってことだろ
残念だが 敵の手の中で
踊らされてるんだ 俺たちは
We've fallen straight into their hands.
Is that all?
それだけか？
え？
Huh?
Is that all they said?
奴らの会話はそれだけか？
It's all I heard.
ああ 俺が聞いたのは
なら 問題ない
Then we're fine!
はあ？
バレてないってことだ
They haven't figured our plan out yet.
こっちの作戦はバレてない
奴らの口から磁石の｢じ｣の字も
出てこないんだから
They didn't say anything about magnets.
そ… そりゃそうだけど
Well, yeah, but...
ビクビクするな カイジくん
Chill a bit, Kaiji.
As long as that's all they said, we're fine!
だってそうだろ？今の話を
そのまま素直に取ると そうなる
気がついてないんだ 奴ら
They haven't realized yet!
こちらの磁石入りビール作戦に
They don't know how our magnets work!
なら 前もって わしの挑戦が
知られていようがいまいが
Even if they know I'm out to take down the Bog, it's no big deal!
そんなことは大した問題じゃない
わしの作戦の要 根本が
They don't know the most important part of my plan!
否定されたわけじゃ
ないんだからな
磁石は生きとるんだ
As long as we have the magnets!
それは まあ…
I guess, but...
なら… なら何の問題もない
So there's no problem!
Quit joking around! There's no reason to quit when we're almost there!
今 やめることはない　そうさ
冗談じゃない あと少しなんだから
磁石入りビールを使いだして
６回 ３段目に運んだ
I've made it to the third tray six times since I started with the magnet beer!
５分の１の確率だ
もう来る頃だ　次か その次
It has one in five odds, right?
It's overdue! Next time, or the time after!
しかし どうするつもりだ
ブロックされたら？
And what are you gonna do when they use the block?
敵はまだ策を持ってんだぜ
They still have tricks up their sleeve. Probably an impenetrable defense.
恐らく鉄壁に近い防御を
それを使われたら終わりだ
Once they use that, it's over.
なら ここまでがどうだろうと
もう負けは見えてる
It doesn't matter what's happened, we're beat.
That does sound pretty ominous.
その点は確かに不気味だ
しかし よく考えたら
敵は待ってくれている
But if you think about it, they're waiting.
今 待ってくれてるんだろ？
そのブロックとやらを
They're holding off on that block.
So we still have a chance, right, Kaiji?
出る　今なら
違うか？カイジくん
なら撤退は そのブロックを
されてからでも遅くない
So there's no point in quitting until the block comes out!
作戦タイム終了だ
We're done planning!
あ？
いいのかよ？
Come on. You're playing with someone else's money now. The money you "borrowed".
ここから先は人の金
くすねてきた金なんだぜ？
そういう意味じゃ分岐点
分かれ道なんだよ 今が
You've got a choice to make here.
今 やめれば少なくとも
後ろに手が回ることはない
If you quit now, you can at least stay a free man!
間に合うんだ まだ
You still have a chance!
間に合う？
そうさ　まだ間に合う
I still have a chance?
Yeah! You still have a chance!
What are you talking about?
何に？
え？
間に合うって 何に？
だ… だから その…
What do you mean, I still have a chance?
Well, uh...
Idiot!
バカヤロー！
What the hell do you understand? My 20 million... My 20 million is all gone!
分かってんのか？ああ？
2000万… 2000万…
2000万 いかれちまったんやぞ
What do you mean, I still have a chance!?
今さら何が間に合うっていうんだ
I told you! That money was everything I had! It was my future!
言ったやろ あの金が全てやって
あの金がわしの未来
希望の全てなんや
My only hope!
You think I can wash my hands of it here!?
済むか！
I've lost it all! I can't quit without winning it back!
すりました 負けました
かからんかったで
引き下がれるか！
I've got to win! I can't turn back!
勝たにゃならん
取り返さにゃならんのだ
何としても！
No matter what it takes!
Go for it!
Sakazaki resumes his challenge!
勝負再開　坂崎！
全財産2000万を使い果たし
ついに手を出す他人の金
Having bet his own twenty million, he begins to bet out of someone else's pocket!
緊急調達したマル秘の金 3000万！
The thirty million  he "secured" in a hurry!
I can't lose!
負けられない
そして突入
極限を超えた狂気の世界！
He dives into a world of madness! beyond all limits!
魔の領域へ
The devil's territory!
Kaiji the Movie 2 opens November 5th!
Tell me the truth.
The impossible pachinko machine, the Bog.
To defeat this monster, Kaiji takes on the casino's manager Ichijou.
Original author Nobuyuki Fukumoto joins the writing staff
in this new story of life-or-death games.
This fall, the ultimate entertainment sets Japan abuzz.